<resources>
    <string name="app_name">cosmic_1</string>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="affirmation">affirmation</string>
    <string name="meditation">meditation</string>
    <string name="symtoms">symtoms</string>
    <string name="things">things</string>
    <string name="sonu">sonu</string>
    <string name="quotes">Quotes</string>
    <string name="q1"> Asking for help is a sign of self-respect and self-awareness.</string>
    <string name="q2"> 2Asking for help is a sign of self-respect and self-awareness.</string>
    <string name="q3"> 3A3sking for help is a sign of self-respect and self-awareness.</string>
    <string name="q4"> 4As4king for help is a sign of self-respect and self-awareness.</string>
    <string name="q5"> 5Ask5ing for help is a sign of self-respect and self-awareness.</string>
    <string name="q6"> 6Aski6ng for help is a sign of self-respect and self-awareness.</string>
    <string name="q7"> 7Askin7g for help is a sign of self-respect and self-awareness.</string>
    <string name="q8"> 8Asking8 for help is a sign of self-respect and self-awareness.</string>
    <string name="q9"> 9Asking 9for help is a sign of self-respect and self-awareness.</string>
    <string name="q10"> 10Asking 0for help is a sign of self-respect and self-awareness.</string>
    <string name="heading1"> stress managemt</string>
    <string name="body"> Journaling is a written account of your thoughts and feelings as you navigate everyday life.
The beauty of journaling is that there’s no right or wrong way to do it. It’s a deeply personal experience that can take many forms.
One day, journaling could look like a diary entry, similar to the ones you may have written when you were a teenager. The next day it can be a list of things that bring you joy or a list of goals you want to achieve.
Developing a journaling habit can help you work through your emotions, especially when you’re feeling anxious or sad. It can also help you grow, become more self-aware, and gain meaningful insights.
For these reasons, journaling is one of the best self-improvement tools.
Having said that, it’ll come as no surprise that some of the most successful people in the world, including Richard Branson, Warren Buffet, and Arianna Huffington have kept journals throughout their lives.
Benefits of journaling
While the act of writing things down seems simple enough, the results are powerful. Here are just some of the benefits of keeping a journal. \n\n<b>
1. Improves mental well-being</b> \n\n
The COVID-19 pandemic has brought unprecedented stress and uncertainty into our lives.
During this time, 4 in 10 adults in the US have experienced symptoms of anxiety and depression.
One way to deal with intense emotions and uncertainty during difficult times is to find a healthy outlet for them in the form of a journal. Journaling is proven to have a positive effect on mental health and reduce the effects of anxiety and depression


       \n\n<b> 2. Strengthens the immune system and recovery time</b>\n\n
You’ve likely heard the expression, “An apple a day keeps the doctor away.” Well, it turns out journaling can have the same effect.
In a 2018 Cambridge study, participants were asked to write about their deepest thoughts and feelings surrounding the most stressful or upsetting events in their lives.
Four months later, those who wrote about their experiences for 15 minutes a day reported fewer visits to the doctor and fewer sick days.
Not only is journaling linked to long-term decreases in health problems, but it also helps you heal faster. Another study found that expressive writing helped speed up wound healing in older adults.
  \n\n\n<b> 3. Gives you a place to express gratitude  </b>\n\n
One of the best ways to express gratitude is by keeping a gratitude journal and writing down things you’re thankful for. Gratitude is proven to activate areas of the brain that are connected to positive emotions.
  \n\n\n<b> 4. Helps you work through challenges </b>\n\n
Journaling is proven to help people heal past wounds and challenging experiences.
A recent Duke University study asked participants who experienced a recent traumatic event to undergo a six-week writing ‘intervention.’ This consisted of various writing prompts, including expressive, poetic, transactional, and mindful journaling.
The study found that writing increased participants’ resilience and decreased stress.

\n\n<b>
5. Helps you set and accomplish goals </b>\n\n
One of the most effective ways to achieve your goals is to write them down.
Putting your goals on paper helps you visualize them more clearly. Visualization is a powerful technique used by elite athletes and CEOs. It involves imagining that what you want to achieve is already yours.
In 2020, Dr. Gail Matthews from the Dominican University of California found that people who write down their goals have a higher chance of accomplishing them when compared to those that don’t.
The importance of journaling
The only way to reap all the rewards that come with journaling is to be consistent. This means making journal entries a daily habit rather than an occasional hobby.
Writing daily is a powerful way to do inner work. It can lead to insights and breakthroughs and help you process difficult emotions and situations.
Learning how to write a journal is also a great mindfulness practice because it helps you focus on the present moment. Being present without worrying about the past or future is a very calming and peaceful feeling that relaxes the mind and body.
The calming effects of daily journaling can also help treat emotional exhaustion. For example, incorporating 20 minutes of journaling into your nighttime routine can help you unload heavy feelings of stress before bed.
We could spend all day talking about the many benefits of keeping a journal. But how do you start one?
The process is simple, yet looking at that first blank page of your notebook can feel daunting.\n\n

    \n\n<b>    1. Find the journaling techniques that work for you </b>\n\n
Many people prefer keeping a paper journal because it helps them develop and express ideas more clearly. But putting pen to paper isn’t the only way to journal.
When you first begin writing, it’s important to find the method that works best for you. You may find that the ease of using a laptop makes journaling more enjoyable for you. You also don’t have to limit yourself to one method.
Say you prefer handwriting, but you get a burst of inspiration during your morning commute on the subway. In that case, you can use the notes app on your phone to jot down your thoughts before you forget them.
    </string>
    <string name="body2">

        2. Let go of judgments (write for your eyes only)
There’s no right or wrong way to journal. When you’re writing, it’s important to practice self-compassion and leave your inner critic at the door. Journaling is a judgment-free zone.


</string>

    <string name="next_affirmation">Next Affirmation</string>
</resources>